Guide to the Military Assistance Command, Vietnam Team 58 photograph collection, 1964-1965
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Military Assistance Command, Vietnam Team 58 photograph collection
1964-1965
C0196
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
0.25 linear feet (1 box)
The collection contains 198 black and white photographs measuring 3.75 x 2.5 inches, of MACV Team 58's experience in South Vietnam's Choung Thien province.
United States. Military Assistance Command, Vietnam. Advisory Team 58.
Box 2
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
104 photographs purchased from Between the Covers in August of 2011. An additional 94 photographs donated by Al Short in January 2017.
Historical Information
MACV (Military Assistance Command, Vietnam) was an organization of military personnel, sent to train and assist South Vietnamese armed forces. Originally, the advisors were sent to support the French military in the First Indochina War and were named MAAG (Military Assistance Advisory Group) Indochina. With the withdrawal of French troops from Vietnam, MAAG shifted its focus to the training of South Vietnamese forces in an effort to stem the rising influence of Communism. In 1962 MAAG was replaced by U.S. Military Assistance Command Vietnam (MACV) and had grown from a few hundred advisors to over 3,000. At the time the photographs in this collection were taken (1964-1965), Team 58 was stationed in Vi Thanh in the former Chuong Thien province.
Scope and Content
The collection contains 198 black and white photographs (measuring 3.75 x 2.5 inches) of MACV Team 58 taken by the Administrative NCO and by 1st Lieutenant Al Short in 1964-1965. Photographs in the collection show the day-to-day life in the camp with some images of combat. Photographs of advisors include personnel working in offices, eating meals and enjoying down time, and preparing for a USO show. Several photographs document an assembly with Vietnamese speakers attended by both military advisors and local residents. Photographs also include scenes of the province capital of Vi Thanh, and several photographs taken from an airplane.
Series 1 contains photos taken by one of the Administrative Non-Comissioned Officers in MACV Team 58 in 1965. The series contains five subseries. Subseries 1 contains photographs taken from an assembly in Vi Thanh (probably the transition of the office of province chief from Lieutenant Colonel Diep to Major Nghia according to Al Short); subseries 2 contains photograms of the MACV Team 58 camp; subseries 3 includes Aerial views of Vietnam and images of the camp's runway and pilots; subseries 4 contains images of Vi Thanh,the capital of what was then called Chuong-Thien Province; subseries 5 contains portraits of MAAG Team 58.
Series 2 contains photos taken by Al Short, a 1st Lieutenant in MACV Team 58, in 1964 and 1965, as well as two news articles from 1965. Subseries 1 contains photos from a Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama Team show; subseries 2 contains photos of civic action program activities; subseries 3 contains photos of Vietnamese officials in Choung Thien Province; subseries 4 contains photos of military equipment and aircraft; subseries 5 contains photos of life in Vi Thanh city; subseries 6 contains photos of various Vietnamese military units on operations; subseries 7 contains photos of life in the MACV, Advisory Team 58 compound; subseries 8 contains photos of MACV Advisory Team 58 members; subseries 9 contains photos from an awards ceremony at the MACV Advisory Team 58 compound. Subseries descriptions and arrangement come from Al Short; subseries 10 contains two news articles from Boston from January and May 1965.
Arrangement
The photographs in this collection are arranged by subject. Arrangement of series 2 was done by Al Short.
Series 1: Photos by Administrative NCO, 1965 (pages 1-26)
Series 2: Photos by Al Short, news articles, 1964-1965 (pages 27-51)
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also hold the which includes photographs related to the Vietnam War. and the both contain anti-Vietnam War materials.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
United States. Army--Photographs.
Geographical Names:
Vi Thanh (Vietnam)--Photographs.; Vietnam--Photographs.
Subjects:
Military camps--Photographs.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Photographs.
Document Types:
Aerial photographs.; Group portraits.; Photographic prints.; Portraits.
Contents List
- Series 1: Photos by Administrative NCO (pages 1-26), 1965
  - Subseries 1.1: Vi Thanh Assembly, 1965
    - Assembly speaker 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Man delivering a speech, viewed from behind.
    - Assembly speaker 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Man giving a speech, viewed from right.
    - Assembly speaker 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Assembly stage 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Man delivering a speech, viewed from the point of view of the crowd behind him.
    - Assembly stage 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Assembly crowd 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      View of the crowd at the assembly including millitary personnel and civilians.
    - Assembly crowd 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Alternate view of the crowd at the assembly.
    - Assembly crowd 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Crowd at assembly with banners displaying Vietnamese slogans.
    - Assembly soldiers 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Soldiers at assembly with Vietnamese banner.
    - Assembly soldiers 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 1.2: MACV Team 58 Camp, 1965
    - Bedroom, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Camp bedroom featuring two beds and a nightstand.
    - Weapons, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      M1 carbines and M14 hanging on the wall.
    - Camp bedroom 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Wall of a camp bedroom with dresser and clothing hanging on wall.
    - Camp Bedroom 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Camp bedroom with a bed, table and chairs, dresser and nightstand.
    - Camp mess hall 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Camp mess hall with maps of Choung Thien province on an easel.
    - Camp mess hall 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Building, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Building made of corrugated metal and hit by Viet Cong mortar fire.
    - Entrance gate 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      View of the entrance gate to MACV Team 58 compound. Sign still says MAAG.
    - Camp building 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Building in the camp seen from the side, including sand bag bunker and "gym" workout area.
    - Camp buildings 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Aerial view of the camp including several different complexes of buildings.
    - Camp and jeep, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Army 3/4 ton truck parked in the Southeast corner of the compound behind bunker and reinforcements made of sandbags.
    - Training center, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      View of South Vietnamese Regional Force/Popular Force (RF/PF) training center across the main canal in Vi Thanh, shot from a team jeep.
    - Camp building 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Large building in Vi Thanh.
    - Camp building 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Building in the camp seen from the side.
    - Camp building 4, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Duplicate picture.
    - Camp building 5, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Building in the camp shot from a different angle.
    - Camp building 6, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Building in the camp with corrugated roof.
    - Shed and military advisor, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Small building in the camp with army personnel inside.
    - Repairing camp building, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Building in the camp with corrugated roof. A new worker on a lader is making repairs to the building.
    - Camp buildings 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Major Otis A Moran, Sector Senior Advisor, Major Thomas Lavasseur, Assistant Senior Advisor, and an unidentified individual standing outside several buildings in the camp on a Sunday.
    - Entrance gate 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      View of the entrance gate to MACV Team 58 compound, with a shower and latrine on the right and Vietnamese police serving as gate guards.
    - Camp roofs, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Overhead shot of corrugated roofs with camp name and location printed on it.
    - USO Show 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      USO show in the MACV Team 58 mess hall.
    - USO Show 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - USO Show 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - USO Show 4, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - USO Show 5, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      USO show prepartions.
    - USO Show 6, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - USO Show 7, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mess hall 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Military personnel in a mess hall.
    - Camp shed and 3/4 ton truck, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Small building in the camp with army personnel inside and army 3/4 ton truck.
    - Reparing trailers in courtyard, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Military personnel outside buildings working on trailers.
    - Mess hall 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Military personnel in mess hall.
    - Camp building with Vietnamese Police Guards, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Vietnamese National Police guarding the compound during the day, with shower and latrine building in the background.
  - Subseries 1.3: Aviation and Aerial Photography, 1965
    - Aerial shot 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Image of land, taken from an aircraft. Fires on the ground are farmers burning rice straw in fields after the harvest.
    - Aerial shot 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Aerial shot 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Aerial shot 4, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Vi Thanh airport and aircraft 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Sector L-19 (piper cub) landing at the "new" Vi Thanh airport, completed by Vietnamese engineers in early 1965.
    - Vi Thanh airport and aircraft 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Vi Thanh airport and aircraft 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Military advisors with aircraft, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Two unidentified US NCOs and Major Thomas LeVasseuer standing at the back of an aircraft.
  - Subseries 1.4: Vi Thanh, 1965
    - Advisory Team 58 names, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      List of the names of Advisory Team 58 members written in the sand.
    - Tennis court in Vi Thanh 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Local children on court while military personnel play tennis. Vietnamese Brigade Headquarters is in the background.
    - Tennis court in Vi Thanh 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Military personnel playing tennis. Vietnamese Brigade Headquarters is in the background.
    - Tennis court in Vi Thanh 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - River bank, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      A river bank in Vi Thanh.
    - Store front in Vi Thanh 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Store front in Vi Thanh with local residents and military personel.
    - Store front in Vi Thanh 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Store front in Vi Thanh with local residents.
    - Store front in Vi Thanh 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Street scene of Vi Thanh, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Local residents and military personnel.
  - Subseries 1.5: Portraits, 1965
    - Army personnel, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Major Thomas LeVasseur, Deputy Sector Advisor and a team Administrative NCO posed in uniform.
    - Self portrait, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Unidentified team Administrative NCO taking a picture in the mirror.
    - Water tower 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Military advisor taking pictures from the top of the compound water tower.
    - Water tower 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Water tower 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan sitting in the compound on a Sunday.
    - Gate guards, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Two Vietnamese Police gate guards sitting behind sandbags in the compound entrance, bunker in the background.
    - Captain Clyde Myer at desk, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Captain Clyde Myer sitting at his desk behind a type writer.
    - Group portrait 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Several team members sitting in the mess hall.
    - Unidentified NCO, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Unidentified NCO sitting at a desk or table.
    - Vietnamese interpreter 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Vietnamese interpreterer sitting at a desk with a map of Choung Thien province behind him.
    - 1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan behind the mess hall; generator shed in the rear.
    - Portrait 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Photograph of an Administrative NCO in a stripped shirt.
    - Major Donald Gluck and Major Otis A. Moran, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Major Donald Gluck and Major Otis A Moran (incoming and outgoing Senior Sector Advisors) on a Sunday.
    - Man in bed, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Unidentified lieutenant reading something in bed.
    - Vietnamese interpreter in jeep, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Vietnamese interpreter for Team 58 driving a jeep at the compound.
    - Group portait at meal time, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Group portrait of US and Vietnamese personnel eating a meal, probably at the province chief's home; Major Donald Gluck is second on left.
    - Two men in aircraft, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Two team NCOs sitting in the back of Caribao Aircraft, one man in the forground faces away from the camera.
    - Man getting a haircut, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      A man getting his haircut in the camp.
    - Man at desk, August 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Administrative NCO at his desk in the sector office.
    - Portrait 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Photograph of an Administrative NCO (the photographer of most of the pictures in the collection) in a white tee-shirt.
    - Major Thomas LeVasseur with shovel, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Major Thomas LeVasseur washing a shovel in the rear of the compound.
    - Two men at Brigade HQ, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Captain Whittman and an unidentified officer (rear) at their desks in Brigade HQ.
    - Group portrait volleyball, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Group portrait of army personel playing volleyball in the compound; Major Thomas LeVasseur is on the left.
    - Two gate guards at camp, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Two Vietnamese Police gate guards sitting in the camp behind sandbags.
    - Vietnamese interpreter and Admin NCO, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Vietnamese interpreter and Admin NCO in uniform sitting at a desk in the sector office.
    - Admin NCO with cars, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      An Administrative NCO posing with several cars.
    - Group portrait 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Three NCOs sitting around a table in a bedroom.
    - Man with snake, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Man posing with a Boa constrictor.
    - Water tower 4, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Military advisor on water tower taking pictures.
    - Two men with jeeps, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Two NCOs posed with military jeeps.
    - Portrait 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Photograph of an Administrative NCO in a white shirt in front of a building.
    - Group portrait 3, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Group portrait of military advisors at a party.
    - Men at mess hall, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Two men in the mess hall, one reading and one at a desk.
    - Men in front of a building, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Captain Whittman (seated) and another man standing in front of a camp building.
    - Commo (communications) NCO, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Communications NCO in uniform posed in the mess hall entry.
    - Admin NCO outside, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Administrative NCO outside in the compound posed in front of sandbags.
    - USO speed painter, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      USO speed painter preparing for USO show in the mess hall.
    - Vietnamese interpreter 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Vietnamese interpreter sitting at his desk with a map of Vietnam behind him.
    - Group portrait 4, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Group portrait of (left to right) Lieutenant Colonel Preston, senior advisor, Lieutenant Colonel Diep, province chief, Captain Loi, Vietnamese inelligence officer, Major Donald Gluck, and unidentified NCOs sitting outside.
    - Group portrait 5, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      4 unidentified NCOs sitting outside the rear of the compound with the "gym" in the background.
    - Captains Whitman and Myer, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Captain Whitman seated at desk looking at the camera, Captain Clyde Myer with his back to the camera.
    - Pilot and Major Thomas LeVasseur, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Unidentified USAF Pilot and Major Thomas LeVasseur talking.
- Series 2: Photos by Al Short, news articles (pages 27-51), 1964-1965
  - Subseries 2.1: PSYOP/Culture show, 1965
    - Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama show 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama show at Sub-Sector Location, likely Duc Long.
    - Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama show 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama show 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama show 4, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Vietnamese Army Cultural Drama team members travelling by boat to performance site.
  - Subseries 2.2: Civic programs, 1965
    - Al Short 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short presenting to Vietnamese woman.
    - Military advisors and Vietnamese officials 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Captain Clyde Meyer, Sam Daeli, 1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short, and unidentified Vietnamese Province (Sector) officials.
  - Subseries 2.3: Viet officials, 1965
    - Military advisors and Vietnamese officials 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan and Lieutenant Buu having beer in Vi Thanh with an unidentified Vietnamese man.
    - Lieutenant Buu, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Lieutenant Buu, Sector Logistical Officer.
    - Military advisors and Vietnamese officials 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Captain Loi (Vietnamese Sector Intelligence Officer) and Lieutenant Colonel Zom drinking Budweiser at the MACV compound.
    - Vietnamese officials 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Ken Thien District Chief being promoted to Captain by Province Chief Major Nghia.
    - Vietnamese officials 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Lieutenant Colonel Nguyen Ngoc Diep, Choung Thien province chief.
    - Vietnamese officials 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Lieutenant Tri, Provincial Assistant S-5 in field with his PSYOP team.
  - Subseries 2.4: Military equipment and aircraft, 1965
    - Aircraft 1, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      US Army L-19 on the "new" strip at Vi Thanh.
    - Aircraft 2, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      US Army HUEY-B model gun-ships on the ground at Vi Thanh.
    - Aircraft 3, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      US Army troop carying HUEY helicopters departing with Vietnamese forces from Vi Thanh.
    - Jeep, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Advisory Team 58 Jeep at MACV Team 58 compound gate.
    - "Steam roller", early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      French "steam roller," circa 1910.
    - Boat, early 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Vietnamese Navy Riverine Assault Group (RAG) 26 vessel.
  - Subseries 2.5: Vi Thanh city shots, 1964-1965
    - Vi Thanh, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Main street shops in Vi Thanh alongside the main canal.
    - Central market 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Central market in the early morning.
    - Central market 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Central market fruit vendor.
    - Central market 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Central marketplace after a fire.
    - Children 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Army of the Republic of Vietnam military dependents (4 children).
    - Children 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Army of the Republic of Vietnam military dependents (10 children).
    - Children 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Army of the Republic of Vietnam military dependent (1 child).
    - Army of the Republic of Vietnam compound, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Gate to Army of the Republic of Vietnam 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry Regiment compound.
    - Portrait of a Vietnamese woman, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Old woman holding a government propaganda leaflet in the village near Vi Thanh.
    - Portrait of a Vietmanese man, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Old man in the village near Vi Thanh.
    - Vietnamese woman with newspaper, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Woman reading a newspaper in the village near Vi Thanh.
    - Vi Thanh canal 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      View across the main canal at the east end of Vi Thanh.
    - Vi Thanh canal 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Two US advisors paddling a boat across the main canal at Vi Thanh to go to the Regional Forces/Popular Forces training center.
    - 1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan and Vietnamese children 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan inside the MACV Advisory Team 58 compound gate with local children.
    - US and Vietnamese soldiers, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      US advisor and Army of the Republic of Vietnam soldier buying snacks from street vendors.
    - Vi Thanh canal 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      The main canal in the vicinity of Vi Thanh.
    - Vi Thanh canal 4, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Vi Thanh canal 5, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Boat traffic on the main canal in the vicinity of Vi Thanh.
    - Vi Thanh canal 6, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Water buffalo 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Water buffalo and herder next to the MACV Team 58 Compound.
    - Water buffalo 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Three water buffalo next to the MACV Team 58 Compound
    - Barges 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Large barges from Cambodia hauling rock for the "new" airfield construction at Vi Thanh.
    - Barges 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Barges 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Barge hauling fresh water in Vi Thanh.
    - Popular Force guards, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Popular Force guards at the "new" airfield.
    - MACV Team 58 Compound 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      View out the gate of the MACV Team 58 Compound at sundown.
    - Regional Force blockhouse, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Regional Force block house in the vicinity of Duc Long.
    - Bridge and canal, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      View from a jeep on the bridge at Duc Long crossing the main canal.
  - Subseries 2.6: Various Vietnamese military units, 1965
    - 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry 1, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Army of the Republic of Vietnam 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry regiment in the field in the vicinity of Vi Thanh.
    - 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry 2, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry 3, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry 4, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry 5, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry 6, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Battalion commander of the 2nd Battalion/31st Infantry regiment in the field southwest of Vi Thanh.